{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which of the following articles can be sterilized in an autoclave?", "opta": "Gloves", "optb": "Culture media", "optc": "Dressing material", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following disinfectants act by disrupting microbial membranes?", "opta": "Cationic detergents", "optb": "Halogens", "optc": "Heavy metals", "optd": "Aldehydes", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is best to sterilize heat labile solutions?", "opta": "Dry heat", "optb": "Autoclave", "optc": "Membrane filtration", "optd": "Pasteurization", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The time required to kill 90% of the microorganisms in a sample at a specific temperature is the", "opta": "decimal reduction time", "optb": "thermal death point", "optc": "F value", "optd": "D value", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is best used for long term storage of microbial samples when carried out properly?", "opta": "Storage in a freezer at -10\u00b0C", "optb": "Storage in a freezer at ultra low temperatures (-70\u00b0C)", "optc": "Storage in a refrigerator on an agar slant", "optd": "Storage on a petri plate at room temperature", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a disinfectant containing a heavy metal?", "opta": "Silver nitrate", "optb": "Mercurochrome", "optc": "Copper sulfate", "optd": "Chlorine", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is the most important surface active disinfectants?", "opta": "Amphoteric compounds", "optb": "Cationic compounds", "optc": "Non-ionic compounds", "optd": "Anionic compounds", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which disinfectant would be most effective against Staphylococcus found in a blood spill?", "opta": "Phenol", "optb": "Cetylpyridinium chloride", "optc": "Hexachlorophene", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following substances can sterilize?", "opta": "Alcohol", "optb": "Cetylpyridinium chloride", "optc": "Ethylene oxide", "optd": "Chlorine", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Milk is pasteurized in batch method by keeping it at", "opta": "63\u00b0C for 30 minutes", "optb": "72\u00b0C for 60 seconds", "optc": "73\u00b0C for 30 minutes", "optd": "72\u00b0C for 6 minutes", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Preservation of foods by using salts and sugars works by", "opta": "raising pH", "optb": "lowering osmotic pressure", "optc": "creating a hypertonic environment", "optd": "creating a hypotonic environment", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following items could be sterilized by dry heat sterilization?", "opta": "Intravenous (IV) solution", "optb": "Plastic IV bags", "optc": "Glass pipettes", "optd": "rubber gloves", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following does not kill endospores?", "opta": "Autoclave", "optb": "Incineration", "optc": "Hot air sterilization", "optd": "Pasteurization", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which disinfectant was the most effective against Salmonella\"?", "opta": "Phenol", "optb": "Cetylpyridinium chloride", "optc": "Hexachlorophene", "optd": "Merthiolate", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a canning procedure is not properly followed, which type of microbe is most likely to grow in the canned food?", "opta": "Obligate Aerobe", "optb": "Acidophile", "optc": "Mesophile", "optd": "Obligate Anaerobe", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Bactericidal concentration of phenol is", "opta": "0.25%", "optb": "0.5%", "optc": "0.75%", "optd": "1%", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is most effective for sterilizing mattresses and plastic petri plates?", "opta": "Chlorine", "optb": "Ethylene oxide", "optc": "Glutaraldehyde", "optd": "Ultraviolet radiation", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following skin disinfectant(s) is/are most frequently used?", "opta": "Isopropyl alcohol", "optb": "Ethyl alcohol", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "All of the following are sporicidal except", "opta": "glutaraldehyde", "optb": "ethylene oxide", "optc": "formaldehyde", "optd": "alcohol", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following describes the effect of ionizing radiation on microbes?", "opta": "Changes the 3-dimensional structure of proteins to a 2-dimen-sional form", "optb": "Substantially decreases enzymatic activity, slowing microbial reproduction", "optc": "Induces electrons and protons to jump out of the molecules of the microbe", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The process of making an object free from living organisms including bacterial and fungal spores and viruses is known as", "opta": "pasteurization", "optb": "antisepsis", "optc": "disinfection", "optd": "sterilization", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Media containing spores and thermolabile constituents are sterilized by", "opta": "pasteurization", "optb": "UV radiation", "optc": "dry heat", "optd": "tyndalization", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A(n)____is used to prevent infection by killing or inhibiting pathogen growth on animal tissues.", "opta": "bacteriostatic agent", "optb": "sanitizer", "optc": "disinfectant", "optd": "antiseptic", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One drawback to the use of ultraviolet light as a sterilizing agent is its", "opta": "failure to kill bacteria", "optb": "failure to bacterial spores", "optc": "failure to kill microbes in a closed environment", "optd": "failure to kill microbes located in the center of an object", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Ethylene oxide is used to destroy or kill which of the following microbes?", "opta": "Bacteria", "optb": "Spores", "optc": "Fungi", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following was the first widely used antiseptic and disinfectant?", "opta": "Chlorine", "optb": "Phenol", "optc": "Iodine", "optd": "Alcohol", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a 1:600 dilution of a test compound kills a standard population of Staphylococcus aureus in 10 minutes but not 5 minutes while a 1:60 dilution of phenol kills the population in the same time, what is the phenol coefficient of the test compound?", "opta": "1", "optb": "5", "optc": "10", "optd": "50", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Microbes can be removed from a liquid solution by the process of", "opta": "filtration", "optb": "freeze-drying", "optc": "osmosis", "optd": "desiccation", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is bactericidal?", "opta": "Membrane filtration", "optb": "Ionizing radiation", "optc": "Freeze-drying", "optd": "Deep freezing", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following process can be efficiently carried out by incineration?", "opta": "Sterilization of scalpel blades and needles", "optb": "Sterilization of all glass syringes", "optc": "Sterilization of points of forceps", "optd": "Destruction of contaminated materials", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The organisms retained in the fluids filtered by Seitz filter is", "opta": "Proteus", "optb": "Staphylococcus", "optc": "Clostridium", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following material is sterilized by heating at 160\u00b0C in a hot air oven for one hour?", "opta": "Swab sticks", "optb": "All-glass syringes", "optc": "Oils and jellies", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For sterilization of which material gamma rays can be used?", "opta": "Catheters", "optb": "Plastic syringes", "optc": "Canulas", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is sterilized with the help of glutaraldehyde?", "opta": "Thermometers", "optb": "Bronchoscopes", "optc": "Cystoscopes", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The time in minutes at a specific temperature needed to kill a population of cells is the", "opta": "decimal reduction time", "optb": "thermal death point", "optc": "thermal death temperature", "optd": "F value", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is a limitation of the autoclave?", "opta": "It takes too long to sterilize", "optb": "It lacks the ability to inactivate viruses", "optc": "It lacks the ability to kill endospores", "optd": "It will destroy heat labile materials", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following has most heat resistant spores?", "opta": "Clostridium histolyticum", "optb": "Clostridium perfringens", "optc": "Bacillus stearothermophilus", "optd": "Bacillus cereus", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The lowest temperature that kills all microorganisms in a liquid suspension in 10 minutes is known as the", "opta": "decimal reduction time", "optb": "thermal death point", "optc": "thermal death temperature", "optd": "thermal death time", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following tests is designed to simulate the natural conditions under which the disinfectants are used in hospitals?", "opta": "Phenol coefficient test", "optb": "Minimum inhibitory concentration test", "optc": "Capacity test", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Steam exposure of a material at 100\u00b0C for 20 minutes for three consecutive days is known as", "opta": "inspissation", "optb": "tyndallization", "optc": "autoclaving", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following material is sterilized by use of red heat?", "opta": "Soiled dressings", "optb": "Inoculating wires and loops", "optc": "Glass slides", "optd": "All-glass syringes", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following methods will not sterilize?", "opta": "Aqueous glutaraldehyde for 10 hours", "optb": "Dry heat at 171\u00b0C for 1 to 2 hours", "optc": "121\u00b0C at 15 lb/in pressure for 15 to 20 minutes", "optd": "100\u00b0C boiling water for 30 minutes", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is/are vapour-phase disinfectant/s?", "opta": "Formaldehyde", "optb": "Ethylene oxide", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Sweet and salty foods frequently don't require refrigeration to prevent spoilage because they have", "opta": "insufficient nutrients", "optb": "low pH", "optc": "high concentration of solutes", "optd": "toxic alkaline chemicals", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Iodophores are mixture of", "opta": "iodine and aldehydes", "optb": "iodine and surface active agents", "optc": "iodine and alcohols", "optd": "iodine and phenols", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following compounds are commonly used as general antiseptics to treat cuts and scratches?", "opta": "Aldehydes", "optb": "Ethylene oxide", "optc": "Halogens", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Complete destruction of the microorganisms is commonly known as", "opta": "disinfection", "optb": "sterilization", "optc": "antisepsis", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}